on behalf of the presedential insurance
company it is my very pleasant duty to
welcome you here
today the face of
prudence an iconic
image known by millions around the world
and representing our company a company
with over 165 years of
History our powerful brand is well known
and highly
regarded we've come a long
way but to really understand the present
we must first understand our
past
1848 industrialization is sweeping
across Europe bringing both uncertainty
and opportunity for all classes there's
a demand for better workers rights
people are looking for a sense of
security and in this year on the 30th of
May a group of Victorian gentlemen
respond to these turbulent Times by by
forming the credential Mutual Assurance
investment and Loan Association its aim
to infix habits of prudence among many
individuals to represent the values of
the business the figure of prudence is
adopted as the symbol of the company to
this day she still carries her Arrow
signifying strength of purpose serpent
the ancient symbol of wisdom and mirror
representing
self-awareness
1854 the company widens its reach by
opening its industrial Branch
introducing a new concept Penny policies
for the industrial workingclass
population to build the business the
company introduces a new breed of
salesmen who travel door Todo armed with
Statistics and tables the men from the
pr and with this new market sales grow
dramatically
1871 the company is the first in the
city of London to employ women as
Clarks through the 1870s the company
grows considerably in 1873 there are 47
agents by 1888 there are
10,609 by 1879 the company has outgrown
its premises at Ludgate Hill and moves
into the Striking purpose-built hoben
bars
headquarters by 1898 credential has
become the number one life company in
the United Kingdom with almost £3
million in accumulated funds it's now at
the heart of everyday life nearly one in
three households has a policy with the
pr April 14th 1912 SS Titanic SNS on its
maiden voyage credential promptly pays
out claims on 292 passengers hardly any
disaster could occur without credential
in some way providing security to the
deprived and bereft
by the end of the first world war
credential has paid claims representing
almost a third of the British soldiers
killed in 1919 Prudential offers General
insurance for the first time which
enables the company to start an
extraordinary International
expansion in India in 1923 the first
overseas life branch is established with
the first policy being sold to a tea
planter in assab
the business soon covered the whole of
the subcontinent with offices in Bombay
Kolkata salon and
Delhi in
1924 Prudential expands to Malaysia and
by 1931 a branch is established in
raffle Square Singapore Prudential
starts selling Life policies in Africa
in 1932 and within 3 years the area
overseen from the head office in
Johannesburg reaches from Cape Town to
Northern Uganda some 4,000 miles by 1939
credentials overseas business is
rivaling the success of its UK
operations by the end of the second
world war credential has paid £55
million in claims on nearly 110,000
deaths 1949 the famous man from the pru
advertising campaign is
launched 1967 12 million people watched
the first ever credential commercials on
British television the man from the pr
is truly established as a household name
talk it over with theand from the
presential throughout the 70s and 80s
presedential continues to grow and
respond to customers changing needs in
1986 credential gains a firm foothold in
the United States the world's largest
life insurance and retirement savings
market with the acquisition of Jackson
National Life Insurance Company with 78
million baby boomers reaching retirement
over the next 20 years Jackson is well
placed to help them meet their needs for
retirement
income 1994 is a milestone year as
credential recognizing the high
potential for growth and expansion
across Asia establishes credential
Corporation Asia the regional head
office in Hong Kong sets out to expand
operations Beyond Malaysia Singapore and
Hong Kong businesses are soon
established in Indonesia
Thailand Vietnam and the Philippines in
the UK in 1999 credential strengthens
the group's Investment Management
opportunities with the acquisition of
fund managers m&g m&g itself has a long
history of innovation in 1931 the
company launched the first ever unit
trust in the United
Kingdom over the next 12 years
credential is to become the leading
international life insurer in Asia
expanding into 13 markets and meeting
the savings and protection needs of a
fast growing middle class across the
region credential has established strong
distribution channels including
Partnerships with banks across the
region and an extensive network of
trained
agents 2012 credentials Asia Asset
Management business one of the leading
fund managers in the region is rebranded
as East Spring Investments Paving the
way for its expansion into the US in the
same year
in the United Kingdom credential is a
leading life and pensions provider to
around 7 million customers with a focus
on pensions saving and
Investments credential now has around 24
million insurance customers over 26,000
employees more than 400,000 agents in
Asia four Stock Exchange listings in
London Hong Kong New York and Singapore
and more than 400 billion of assets
under management
we've come a long way not only with the
expansion of our business but also our
work in giving back to the communities
we live and work in today credential is
a company with a broader scope a wider
Geographic spread and greater investment
power than could ever have been imagined
in 1848 but our founding principles of
Integrity security and Prudence still
guide us in promoting long-term
Financial Security for our customers and
building social and economic value you
in our communities around the world